Farband Labor Zionist Order 0011.003.003b
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Farband Labor Zionist Order
1914-1989
0011.003.003b
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
0.5 Cubic feet 1 Box
This is a collection of manuscripts and documents related to the Farband Labor Zionist Order 61 of Hartford, CT. It contains journal ledgers, cemetery plot records, meeting programs, constitution and by-laws pamphlets, and other related letters and documents. In 1914, the Zionist cause in Hartford was strengthened through the formation of a Hartford Branch of the Jewish National Labor Alliance, later known as the Farband Labor Zionist Order 61. The charter members were Benjamin Bialeck, Isaac Garber, Abraham Glick, Isaac J. Jacobson, David Resident, Samuel Rosenthal, Davis Soifer and Abraham Weiner. In 1964, the Farband celebrated its fiftieth anniversary.
In 1914, the Zionist cause in Hartford was strengthened through the formation of a Hartford Branch of the Jewish National Labor Alliance, later known as the Farband Labor Zionist Order 61. The charter members were Benjamin Bialeck, Isaac Garber, Abraham Glick, Isaac J. Jacobson, David Resident, Samuel Rosenthal, Davis Soifer and Abraham Weiner. In 1964, the Farband celebrated its fiftieth anniversary.
Scope and Contents note
Box 1: [arranged by series folders]
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ About this collection
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Anniversaries/ 50th Anniversary of Chapter, 1964
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Constitution and By-laws
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Cemetery Plot Records, 1977-1989
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Cemetery Plot Records, no date
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Financial Information/ Cash Disbursements Journal, 1966-1988
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Financial Information/ Check Register, 1986-1993
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Meeting Programs
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Members and Membership/ Membership List 1989
Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Miscellaneous [includes 1946 Report of the Anglo-American Committee of Enquiry regarding the problems of European Jewry and Palestine]
Related Archival Materials note
Related JHSGH Collections:
Zionism collection
Samuel Hoffenberg collection
Abraham Goldstein collection
Zionist Organization of America collection
Segal, Louis; Soifer, Joseph H., b.1906/9/24, Hartford, CT; Tabatsky, Abraham; Wittel, Samuel; Zeldis, Louis, 12/4/1900, Lokshivka, Ukraine, Russia; Farband Labor Zionist Order; Labor Zionism; Zionism
- Series I: Farband Records and Manuscripts
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ About this collection, undated
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Anniversaries/ 50th Anniversary of Chapter, 1964
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Constitution and By-laws, undated
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Cemetery Plot Records, 1977-1989
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Cemetery Plot Records, no date, undated
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Financial Information/ Cash Disbursements Journal, 1966-1988
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Financial Information/ Check Register, 1986-1993
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Meeting Programs, undated
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Members and Membership/ Membership List 1989
  - Farband Labor Zionist Order/ Miscellaneous [includes 1946 Report of the Anglo-American Committee of Enquiry regarding the problems of European Jewry and Palestine], undated